Hi everyone and welcome. Singapore is
becoming a hub for global wealth and
that means more clients with complex
needs, crossber considerations and high
expectations. I'm joined by four
outstanding private client advisers,
Amanda, Khen, Sakshi and Jean, who work
closely with these clients every day.
They'll be sharing what they are seeing
on the ground, how they build trust and
what it really takes to deliver value in
this space. So let's dive in. We are
seeing a growing influx of high net
worth uh clients coming into Singapore
from offshore and also our local base.
Let's start with what actually looks
like on the ground. What kind of high
net worth clients are you meeting today?
Where are they from? And what are they
really looking for when they come to
someone like you? Maybe we start first
with Amanda.
>> Okay. My clients are mainly from
Singapore and also have offshore clients
that are from China and Taiwan. What
most of my offshore clients are looking
out for is more than just a financial
advice as many of them are in the midst
of relocating and building their new
lives here with their families and at
the same time trying to understand a new
and different financial system. So
that's where my role come in to not just
offer financial advice but to help them
feel secure and understood. And one
thing I realized that what worked well
for them back at home doesn't always
apply here. Many of them do miss out on
important financial planning gaps and
that's where I will help them realize
these gaps and explain it to them so
that they are able to make well-informed
decisions. But at the end of the day I
realize that most of them um they are
just not just looking for a product but
someone that they can trust on and make
things less overwhelming for them. And
that's also what I aim to deliver to
provide clarity, confidence, and someone
that they can trust on.
>> Tell us your secret. How do you usually
find these high net worth clients? And
when you first meet them, how do you
start building trust early on?
>> Okay. So, most of my clients actually
come through referral and
recommendations from my existing clients
that I've built strong relationship with
over the years. So, I do take my time to
understand them. Um to keep those
connections going, I actually host small
gatherings where they can bring their
family and friends along so that these
are the moments that we can get to know
each other. I get to understand their
stories, learn what matters to them and
most importantly being present together.
>> Colleen, you want to add on to a point?
>> Yeah. So I know most of my high net
worth clients through networking across
my various interests. So I have a wide
range of interests. Um it really ranges
from wine tasting to food events and
even to snowboarding. So it's pretty
interesting. Um, so a lot of people have
been asking me, hey, how do you get to
know all these high level clients? And I
was like, yeah, it's true, snowboarding.
Um, and it's very easy for me to
participate in such activities because I
truly enjoy these activities. So, um, I
also do host them quite a lot at my home
because I believe that once you invite
people into your home, into your life,
they'll be ready to welcome you back
into their lives. So, that's where um, I
meet all my high net worth clients as
well. Um, I think it's very important to
be their friend first so that they can
trust you. um and just just be able to
relate well to you.
>> Wow. Nice. Be their friend first. So,
what's one thing that really worked for
you when you're meeting a new client? Um
something simple that made a big
difference.
>> I think something that really worked for
me um and that is unfortunately um some
a little bit underrated is that um I
listen and I remember. So, say for
example, a client um she has chat with
me that um maybe her child has fallen
sick or um which school her child has
enrolled into. I'll remember that and I
always remember to check in. Um this may
seem like a very simple gesture but um I
think it means a lot to the client
because it lets them know that you are
really interested in every aspect of
their lives. So every time I meet them
um it's really not to um open a plan or
um you know to share anything. It's
really just to have an open honest
conversation with them um and really
just to develop uh meaningful and strong
friendships with them.
>> Amanda, you want to add on to a point?
Actually, same thing goes um the biggest
difference is about me to be a friend
first to them rather than advisor to
make them feel that we really care about
them. So that when they realize that we
are not there to rush to sell something
but genuinely being there to walk
through the whole process with them
that's where the real relationship will
form.
>> Can feel the sincerity in both your
answers being your friends with your
customers. Um so let's shift gears and
now many of these clients have wealth
that spans across multiple countries and
insurance can be more than just
protection. It can be part of a bigger
wealth strategy as you all know. So
maybe we start with uh saki first. How
do you help clients see insurance not
just as a product but as a tool to
protect or pass on wealth?
>> You're absolutely right. Insurance has
totally changed uh gears now. It's more
of a strategic tool for legacy planning.
Not just preserving your wealth, but
conserving it and passing it on through
generations through trust and continuity
planning. Once the customer understands
this that now the idea is about legacy
planning and taking care of the
long-term impact, the conversation
completely shifts. They are more open to
understand this because it's the most
taxefficient and tax-free form of
preserving and passing on your wealth.
No, really good. Jean, you want to add
on the point?
>> Yeah, I totally agree with her. So,
usually I'll shift the conversation from
buying a plan to actually having
building a legacy itself. So, I'll
actually let them know that having a
insurance plan actually help them to um
protect their assets from unforeseen
risk um maybe for business continuity
and also of course um most powerfully
pass their wealth actually in a very tax
efficient and structured way. Yeah. And
usually I often tell them that um
insurance is not just about what you
leave behind but it's how you leave
behind.
>> So Jim uh was there a moment where
insurance really made a difference for
your client?
>> Yes. Yeah. I have a client who is a
business owner. he actually bought the
insurance uh substantial legacy plan and
is actually to actually equalize the
inheritance for his family and years
later he actually passed on and they
actually preserved the business without
selling all the assets um under
pressure. So to me I think this is this
moment actually reminded me that good
planning isn't about predicting the
future but actually is the protecting
the people in it.
>> Actually what about you? So very
recently I went through this that a very
dear client and a friend uh came to me
sharing that a colleague of his passed
away uh at an very early age of 43
because of a heart attack while on a run
over the weekend and now the family has
to re relocate back to the home country
with a very li limited amount of
corporate coverage. He was full of
thankfulness and gratitude that few
years back I persuaded him and convinced
him to take a personal term plan for
himself and the spouse
and he just mentioned this to me that I
was also not convinced on this thought
but you convinced me. This totally
resonated with me and I have been
keeping this thought in mind in every
meeting henceforth
because it makes me believe that what
I'm doing when I'm asking my clients the
tough question, it's the right thing to
go ahead with.
>> Wow, these are really powerful stories
that highlight just how real and
personal wealth planning can become,
right? Um so maybe over to um Jean. How
was your role as an adviser changed in
this as this space grows? What do
clients now expect from you that's
different from before?
>> So, they actually see me more um more
like a strategic partner, not like a
product specialist. And of course, I
offer them a lot of insights across the
markets and of course it's like a
one-stop service like even for text and
also trust companies as well. So, um
they expect me to be resourceful. Yeah.
So they come to me just via to text like
just right this morning I have a
conversation with one of the group CEO
of Singapore hospital. So um I also
asked him this question because I'm
having this conversation with you guys
today. So um he actually told me that
what high net worth or ultra high net
worth uh clients are looking for is
mainly um really efficiency and they
want to be reachable for the the
consultant to be reachable just even by
WhatsApp. Yeah. So I think it's it's not
just about um the planning but it's
actually the trust you need. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Si your views on this.
>> Absolutely. Now the high net worth
customers have become much more savvy.
They understand what they are looking
for. So our roles have become much
deeper. They are more than willing to
share their financials transparently
which makes it much easier. At the same
time it shows the amount of trust that
they are showing on you. So you have to
become their confidant more and offer
them solution which best suit them and
that's where our role has become very
important. And of course we are all in a
global world now. We have uh expats
moving here from various countries who
will maybe live here for a short while
and move across. So we have to talk
about long-term uh impact and long-term
continuity of their wealth preservation
and uh growth propositions.
Now we all know that this space is
highly competitive right the high net
worth clients can be very cautious and
they do their homework and earning their
trust doesn't come easy so maybe we
start with Amanda again how would you
say is the hardest part about earning
trust with high net worth clients and
how do you handle it
>> so for many of my high net worth clients
insurance is just one part of a much
larger picture they really want someone
that can anticipate and assist them to
ensure that they wealth is protected,
preserved and passed on, especially when
it matters the most and also in
unexpected situations. How would their
funds and assets be actually be managed
after? They might appear to be rare
guarded at first because they want to
know that the person sitting across them
truly understand their priorities and
act in their best interest and not just
offer one size fit all solution. So I
focus on understanding their world,
their concerns, their values and when
they feel heard and seen that's when
their trust start to form.
>> It's very good. Um Jean, do you have the
similar situation?
>> So actually the hardest part in earning
is the right of in their circle. So to
me I think this client um value privacy
and control and what works for me was
actually patient, consistency and never
rushing the sale. So I actually focus on
listening deeply. Yeah. and I actually
show up with value even when there's no
transaction on the table. So actually
over time trust was actually built not
in my pitch but it's over my presence.
>> Now we know that clients are changing
right and whether it's their bicepet
their needs or how they want to be
served. What's something that you've
noticed lately in this segment and how
have you adapted to keep up? You go to
Colleen.
>> Uh yeah so I've noticed that actually
the lines between high net worth and
ultra high net worth have been
narrowing. Um and because of that um a
lot of my high net worth clients have
actually reached out to me and now they
want the same level of um integrated
solutions um similar to that of ultra
high net worth um and that includes um I
think what is really really on the table
about multigenerational planning. So um
in in lie of that I've actually been
taking on more causes in estate planning
so that I can better equip myself um
really just to provide um good
information and also to provide my
clients with um a comprehensive um suite
of services because nowadays it's not
really about you know growing your
wealth. It's a lot more about preserving
it um not not only for yourself but
really for future generations.
>> Jen, you want to add on to a point?
>> Okay. So for more high net worth clients
especially the next generation they
actually seek for more purposedriven
planning and also it's not about
accumulation anymore it's actually about
impact so I always adapt more wavering
uh legacy planning for into our
conversation and of course from
charitable giving and of course
educating their children and also uh
aligning everything with their personal
values which is very important
especially for high net worth. So I
actually always stay try to stay visible
through um leadership and digital
channels as well so that um the next
generation is listening.
>> So thank you everyone for opening up and
sharing your so honestly today. I'm
genuinely heartened by what I heard
today. Um not just the depth of your
experience but how each and every one of
you show up for your client every day
with clarity and intention. It's clear
to me that this high net worth and
international wealth space demands more
than just technical knowledge. It
demands foresight, empathy, and a deeper
understanding of what truly matters to
the people we serve. Their families,
their values, their needs, and their
future. And the best advisers like the
ones we have here today uh are the ones
who stay ahead, right? And you guys
think for your clients, walk with them
every step of the way. Thank you for
showing up and showing what it really
looks like in action. I'm confident this
conversation will inspire others to
raise the bar, not just on what you do,
but how you lead as well. But before we
wrap things up, um, one last question
for everyone. Um, in one line, what's
your best piece of advice for advisers
out there looking to break into the high
net worth space? Maybe we start with
Sakshi. So be ready to ask the difficult
questions and the right conversation and
solution will follow. That's my one
piece of advice to people who want to
break through in this category.
>> Gene,
>> so to self high net worth you must first
think like one and of course solve
problems beyond products and also earn
trust beyond transactions. Kelly um
>> I would advise the advisers not to be
intimidated by these clients. Um even
though they are high net worth, they are
just humans like you and me. So in fact,
I would really encourage um them to
enjoy the interaction with them, enjoy
the conversation with them and really
just be genuine in your relationship
with them.
>> And finally, Amanda,
>> I think it's always important to be
ready so that when the opportunity
comes, we can have that fruitful and
genuine conversations with these people.
So thank you again. I truly enjoyed this
session with all of you. I am confident
that you'll keep inspiring others in
this space as well. Thank you very much.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.